<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ethnobotany on PersephoneKarnstein.github.io</title><link>https://example.org/tags/ethnobotany/</link><description>Recent content in Ethnobotany on PersephoneKarnstein.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:07:07 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/ethnobotany/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two Drinks That Never Were: Native Alcohol Traditions in the Pacific Northwest</title><link>https://example.org/post/elderberry-chiton/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:07:07 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/post/elderberry-chiton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you ever find yourself reading through the Wikipedia article on &amp;ldquo;Alcohol and Native Americans&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;The History of Alcoholic Beverages,&amp;rdquo; you may find the following passages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the northwest, the Kwakiutl of Vancouver Island produced a mildly alcoholic drink using elderberry juice, black chitons, and tobacco.[57] Despite the fact that they had little to no agriculture, both the Aleuts and Yuit of Kodiak Island in Alaska were observed making alcoholic drinks from fermented raspberries.[56]&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Artificial Saliva and Ethnobotany</title><link>https://example.org/post/artificial-saliva/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 19:42:45 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/post/artificial-saliva/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Look, sometimes you need quite a large volume of artificial saliva for very normal reasons. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there. In my case, it&amp;rsquo;s because I was researching pre-contact fermentation practices in the Americas, and wanted an alternative to manually chewing starchy base ingredients (corn in the case of chicha, or mesquite beans in the specific case I was researching &amp;ndash; more on that later.) What if, I thought, instead of manually chewing the beans I could instead put them in something like a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tiger-Mochi-Machine-Sheng-Force/dp/B0152W13S8"&gt;mochi machine&lt;/a&gt; with my artificial saliva, and pseudo-masticate them that way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>