<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>History on PersephoneKarnstein.github.io</title><link>https://example.org/tags/history/</link><description>Recent content in History on PersephoneKarnstein.github.io</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:49:34 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hooch</title><link>https://example.org/post/hooch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:49:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/post/hooch/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Xutsnoowú Ḵwáan,&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; a tribe of the Tlingit people located on Admiralty Island, Southeast Alaska, is unfortunately best know to white America for one thing: they are the origin of the word &amp;ldquo;hooch.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When researching &lt;a href="https://example.org/post/elderberry-chiton"&gt;claims of pre-contact fermentation practices in the Pacific Northwest&lt;/a&gt;, I came across the following quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Public efforts at prohibiting liquor to the Indian population of the coast were further complicated by the purchase of Alaska by the United States in 1867. The American troops sent to occupy the area, as well as others attracted to it, proved to be poorly disciplined and given to drunkenness, wild depredations, and gross immorality. Smuggling of liquor to the new territory became a common practice, along with bootlegging to the Indian population. However, perhaps an even more significant event was the introduction to the Indians of a technique for home-brewing liquor, reputedly by an intemperate soldier who had deserted or had been discharged from the military post at Fort Wrangell. This brew, known as hoochinoo, was concocted from a variety of ingredients, such as molasses, flour, dried apples, rice, potatoes, salmonberries, blackberries, yeast powder, and sometimes hops. Sufficient water was added to the selected ingredients to make a thin batter. After fermentation took place, a sour, muddy, highly alcoholic liquor was produced. Distillation was accomplished through using coal-oil cans for retorts and kelp for condensation tubes. The Alaska Indians distilled hoochinoo for the white trade as well as for themselves, the technique soon diffused southward throughout the coastal area and inland and became the source of liquor for many bands.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Two Drinks That Never Were: Native Alcohol Traditions in the Pacific Northwest</title><link>https://example.org/post/elderberry-chiton/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:07:07 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/post/elderberry-chiton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you ever find yourself reading through the Wikipedia article on &amp;ldquo;Alcohol and Native Americans&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;The History of Alcoholic Beverages,&amp;rdquo; you may find the following passages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the northwest, the Kwakiutl of Vancouver Island produced a mildly alcoholic drink using elderberry juice, black chitons, and tobacco.[57] Despite the fact that they had little to no agriculture, both the Aleuts and Yuit of Kodiak Island in Alaska were observed making alcoholic drinks from fermented raspberries.[56]&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>